Ollie Wright Game Designer/Programmer

Wallingford, Oxfordshire

Portfolio: ollieportfolio.com

PROFILE

As a game developer with 6 years of experience with game creation, I have strong foundations in a number of design disciplines (specialising in systems, level, and technical), and programming experience following industrial practices. I graduated with a First Class **degree** in computer games technology, creating a number of the highest graded games in my class, and have showcased a TIGA Best Student Game 2024 award winning group project at the Barclays Game Frenzy 2024 created alongside Frontier Developments, and a solo project at my university's Graduate Showcase the year prior, leading to acclaim and mentorship from developers at Larian Studios. My commitment to learning is demonstrated by my most recent project of building a portfolio website in order to teach myself HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

Curation, Curation Team — Design and generalist Programming September 2023 - Present

Curation is a museum management simulation game originally created alongside Frontier Developments as a university project. I focused on creating NPCs that displayed personality, encouraging emergent gameplay through their behaviour, and the underlying system/tech design of the game. This project was showcased at the Barclays Game Frenzy 2024 event in Canary Wharf, and won the TIGA award for Best Student Game 2024. The game is now being further developed for release on digital storefronts. Skills: Unity, C#, Modular AI behaviour, Technical Design, System Design, QA

Press Space, University Project — Solo (design, code, art)

February 2023 - May 2023

Press Space is a satirical branching narrative game, inspired by The Stanley Parable. The game was designed to critique the relationship between players and developers, as well as the concept of free will within games. It was praised for its design/documentation by developers at Larian Studios after being showcased at the UoP Graduate Showcase 2023. Skills: Design for game feel, C#, Narrative design, Level design, Full stack development

Cedrik's Crown, University Project — Lead Designer & QA

October 2022 - January 2023

Cedrik's Crown is a 2-4 player dungeon crawler RPG board game. The enemy encounters were balanced utilising a program written by myself in C++. I focused mostly on the core gameplay loop and the player experience, in addition to playtesting and iterating extensively to ensure balance and consistent player engagement.

Skills: Design principles and balancing, Team leadership, C++, QA

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth, Portsmouth — First Class degree in Computer Games Technology (BSc) - September 2021 - July 2024 Graduated with a 4.16 GPA, with each year module mark average being First Class

The Henley College, Henley — A-Levels – May 2021

Maths (A) Economics (A) Computer Science (A)



ollieswright02@gmail.com



+44 7415 346 751



in <u>linkedin.com/in/ollieswright</u>



github.com/OllieGuy

PROFICIENCIES

Visual Studio 2022/VSCode Unity & PlasticSCM Unreal Engine Git/GitHub C#

HTML/CSS/JavaScript Jira/Confluence Adobe Photoshop Adobe Premiere Pro

SOFT SKILLS

Working with small and medium sized teams to strict

people at conferences and

Effective communication, with

Very strong work ethic and willingness to learn

Positive attitude/outlook and

INTERESTS

Full stack Game Development

Design iteration and consultation with small teams

Media Theory and films

Video and board gaming